They've just parted ways.
Rozchodzą się.
Which one should I follow?
Za kim iść?
Okay, got it.
Rozumiem.
I'll follow the man.
Pójdę za mężczyzną.
Picking up a woman, huh?
Poderwał kogoś?
Oh, man.
Ale jestem gapa.
I'm so dense that I didn't even notice.
Nawet cię nie zauważyłem.
AUTHOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
AUTOR: HITOSHI IWAAKI
SOMETHING WICKED THIS WAY COMES
ZŁEGO COŚ SIĘ SKRADA
I need your help.
Potrzebuję twojej pomocy.
The last thing he said was that he was going
Powiedział, że idzie do piwnicy tego budynku.
But I lacked the courage to go down there myself--
Brakowało mi odwagi, by pójść tam samemu.
That's why we told you that you're in way over your head!
Uprzedzaliśmy cię, że ta sprawa cię przerasta.
Well?
Widzisz coś?
No.
Nie.
None of my kind is nearby.
Nikogo z mojego gatunku.
There's no one here.
Nikogo tu nie ma.
Something smells awful.
Coś tu cuchnie.
It can't be.
Nie może być.
No way.
Niemożliwe.
Shinichi, one incoming!
Shinichi, jeden się zbliża.
Two hundred meters. Hundred and eighty meters.
Dwieście metrów. Sto osiemdziesiąt metrów.
It's fast.
Jest szybki.
It's probably in a car.
Zapewne jedzie autem.
If we go out now, we'll come face to face by the entrance.
Możemy go dopaść przy wejściu.
Crap!
Cholera!
We've got to hide!
Chowajmy się!
It's brought lunch.
Ma ze sobą przekąskę.
Yuck. What is this place?
Co to za miejsce?
Never mind that.
Nie zwracaj uwagi.
Just stand over there, will you?
Stań tutaj, okej?
Like this?
O tak?
Yeah, that's great.
Tak, świetnie.
What's this about? You're kind of weird.
Co robisz? Jesteś trochę dziwny.
Don't go out there, Shinichi.
Nie idź tam, Shinichi.
Why is it hiding there?
Czemu się tam chowa?
Well, whatever.
Nieważne.
So…
Więc…
The moment of truth when they eat humans.
Zaraz zobaczymy, jak ją pożera.
Stop!
Przestań!
What?
Co jest?
You're not one of us?
Nie jesteś jednym z nas?
Watch out!
Uważaj!
He's not human! Get away from him!
On nie jest człowiekiem!
Why, you!
Ożeż ty!
Humans!
Ludzie.
Listen, Shinichi.
Shinichi, zapomnij, że tu jestem.
If we take the time to discuss strategy and whatnot, we'll lose.
Nie mamy czasu na omawianie strategii.
Just keep dodging his attacks.
Po prostu rób uniki.
Don't try to defeat him barehanded like you did before!
Nie próbuj pokonać go gołymi rękami, jak wcześniej.
And that'll be enough to win?
To wystarczy?
Good. Your moves aren't bad.
Nieźle się ruszasz.
I think I'll win by having the better mount.
Wygram, bo mam lepszego wierzchowca.
Who are you calling a "mount"?
Kogo nazywasz wierzchowcem?
My kind's weakness lies below the neck. The human portion.
Nasz najsłabszy punkt leży pod szyją.
We'll eventually win, as long as we keep that part protected.
Żeby wygrać, należy go chronić.
I couldn't save her.
Nie uratowałem jej.
This is nothing new, though.
To nie było nic nowego.
I knew what was going on.
Wiedziałem, co się dzieje.
I knew
A mimo tego nic nie zrobiłem.
In any case, we've got trouble.
Mamy kłopoty.
Given the male's attitude,
To musi być jedno z miejsc żeru wyznaczonych przez grupę Hirokawy.
That means our actions constitute an act of war against them.
To, co tu zrobiliśmy, będzie odebrane jako akt wojny.
Are you listening, Shinichi?
Słuchasz mnie?
I was wrong.
Myliłem się.
What?
Co?
I was wrong to…
Niepotrzebnie…
Anyway, we need to get clear of this place as soon as possible.
Musimy się stąd zmywać.
Kuramori-san, you're not going to stop now, are you?
Kuramori-san, chyba się pan teraz nie podda, prawda?
There's a detective I've met before.
Napotkałem już jednego detektywa.
I think his name is Hirama.
Nazywa się Hirama.
I'm sure he'll listen to you.
Na pewno pana wysłucha.
He even suspected me of being one of the monsters.
Podejrzewał, że byłem jednym z potworów.
Hey, don't get any strange ideas.
Oby nic ci nie strzeliło do głowy.
What's so strange about it?
Niby co? Będziemy walczyć z grupą Hirokawy.
Do you hear yourself?
Czy ty siebie słyszysz?
We may be in an extremely precarious situation right now.
Jesteśmy w bardzo niebezpiecznej sytuacji.
We'll use the footage Kuramori-san recorded as evidence
Nagranie Kuramori-sana będzie dowodem,
to get the police to search the building from top to bottom.
który skłoni policję do przeszukania budynku.
Don't be ridiculous.
Nie żartuj. Na tym nagraniu jesteśmy także my.
I can't stand this anymore!
Mam tego dość!
Do you want your father to be killed, too?
Chcesz, żeby zginął twój ojciec?
What?
Co?
What do you mean by that?
Czemu tak mówisz?
Don't worry.
Spokojnie.
I was wrong.
Myliłem się.
Like you all said, I'm in over my head.
Mieliście rację. To mnie przerasta.
I'm a small-timer.
Jestem płotką.
I shouldn't have gotten involved in all this.
Niepotrzebnie się w to mieszałem.
I'll destroy all the evidence I've gathered so far.
Zniszczę wszystkie zebrane dowody.
But why?
Dlaczego? Widział pan, co się stało.
Didn't that mean anything to you?
To nic dla pana nie znaczy?
Of course it did!
Wręcz przeciwnie.
My teeth are still chattering!
Wciąż się trzęsę.
Anyone who saw that and still thinks they can fight them is crazy!
Ktokolwiek myśli, że może z nimi walczyć, jest szalony!
You're no longer a normal human being!
Nie jesteś już zwyczajnym człowiekiem.
Even that fight,
Walczyłeś z nim jak potwór z potworem.
I'm just a weak human being.
Ja jestem tylko słabym człowiekiem.
I have neither the strength nor the courage to protect myself.
Brakuje mi siły i odwagi, by się ochronić.
I'm not you, okay?
Nie jestem jak ty.
From this day on,
Wyrzucę z pamięci te potwory, Tamurę Reiko i ciebie.
Don't look at me like that.
Nie patrz tak na mnie.
I have a wife and child.
Mam żonę i dziecko.
I know I made a grandiose speech
Wiem, że prawiłem ci kazania o dobru ludzkości.
I'm sorry.
Przepraszam.
Well…
I proszę.
That's a normal human being for you.
Typowy człowiek.
Shut up.
Zamknij się.
You're no longer a normal human being!
Nie jesteś już zwyczajnym człowiekiem.
He's right.
On ma rację.
I'm not normal.
Nie jestem normalny.
What can I do?
Co mogę zrobić?
Shinichi.
Shinichi.
I've said this to you many times already, but let's not engage in futile resistance.
Powtarzam po raz kolejny, nie walczmy z nimi na próżno.
Futile?
Na próżno?
I'm not so sure.
No nie wiem.
We were able to win today.
Dzisiaj wygraliśmy.
That's right! We can win if it's one-on-one!
W walce jeden na jednego mam szansę wygrać.
With my cooperation, you mean.
O ile ci pomogę.
Yes, I can do this.
Dam radę.
I can do anything if I put my mind to it!
Jeśli się postaram, mogę osiągnąć, co tylko chcę.
One by one.
Jeden na jednego.
Right, I can get them one by one!
Załatwię ich po kolei.
I won't ask for help from any other human.
Nie będę prosił o pomoc innych ludzi. Zrobię to sam.
Migi would help me for sure, then.
Migi na pewno będzie za.
No, I will make him help me!
Jeśli nie, zmuszę go.
Call it human ego or whatever you want,
Może przemawia przeze mnie ego,
but I just want to save as many people as I can!
ale chcę uratować tyle osób, ile zdołam.
That would mean a safer world for Murano, too.
Murano będzie żyć w bezpieczniejszym świecie.
Satomi, did you have a fight with Izumi-kun or something?
Satomi, pokłóciłaś się z Izumi-kunem?
I don't think I've seen you two together lately.
Dawno nie widziałam was razem.
It wasn't really a fight, but I guess we just can't trust each other.
Nie nazwałabym tego kłótnią, ale myślę, że nie możemy sobie ufać.
He doesn't look like he can't trust you.
On jest chyba innego zdania.
I don't get him at all!
Nie rozumiem go.
Wait, Satomi!
Poczekaj, Satomi!
I will protect as many people as I can!
Ochronię tyle osób, ile zdołam.
The enemy is formidable.
Nasz wróg jest potężny.
We must deal with him.
Musimy się nim zająć.
Killing him would be a waste,
Zabicie go byłoby marnotrawstwem.
although I couldn't care less about the P.I.
Ale sam detektyw już mnie nie obchodzi.
Nonsense.
Bzdura.
He is, without a doubt, a dangerous foe.
To groźny przeciwnik.
Why would you defend him?
Dlaczego go pani broni?
We are not human.
Nie jesteśmy ludźmi.
Why are our opinions so incompatible?
Dlaczego nie możemy się porozumieć?
Tamura-san,
Tamura-san,
I've heard that you are rearing a human child.
wychowuje pani ludzkie dziecko.
Is that affecting your judgment?
Czy to wpływa na pani osąd?
Isn't it time to dispose of it?
Może należy się go pozbyć.
I can't do that just yet.
Nie mogę tego jeszcze zrobić.
In any event, Izumi Shinichi killed one of us in our dining area.
Izumi Shinichi zabił jednego z nas w miejscu żeru.
We clearly cannot let this go.
Nie możemy tego zignorować.
We should eliminate him.
Musimy go wyeliminować.
I suppose it's unavoidable.
To nieuniknione.
However, I would like his body to be brought back intact.
Ale chciałabym zabrać potem jego ciało.
Why?
Dlaczego?
I would like to dissect him.
Żeby zrobić sekcję.
That was impressive, Gotou-san.
Imponujące, Gotou-san.
Was it Mozart?
To Mozart?
Chopin.
Chopin.
Our target is said to be a formidable match.
Nasz cel będzie nie lada wyzwaniem.
I do think it should be you who handles him, but…
Myślę, że to pan powinien się nim zająć, ale…
If Miki wants to do it, I'll let him.
Jeśli Miki chce to zrobić, pozwolę mu na to.
He just needs more experience.
Musi zdobyć doświadczenie.
What is this?
Co to?
Who are you?
Kim jesteś?
I've got my hands full.
Mam ręce pełne roboty.
You're a monster?
Jesteś potworem?
So that's how I appear to you.
A więc tak mnie widzisz.
But look who's talking.
Ale spójrz na siebie.
Take a look.
Spójrz.
What a nightmare.
Co za koszmar.
Killing parasites, one by one.
Zabiję wszystkie pasożyty po kolei.
How will I convince Migi to help me?
Ale jak przekonać Migiego, by mi pomógł?
Maybe the path of least resistance will be to create a situation
Może powinienem postawić go w sytuacji bez wyjścia.
What?
Co? Spóźnię się na lekcję.
No time for that. My kind, incoming.
Zbliża się ktoś z mojego gatunku.
What? Again?
Znowu?
This is my chance!
To moja szansa.
Okay, let's fight.
Okej, walczymy.
Where is it right now?
Gdzie on jest?
Don't be so eager.
Nie tak szybko.
We're the target.
To my jesteśmy celem.
They're coming straight for us with the intent to kill us.
Oni chcą nas zabić.
And there are three.
Jest ich trójka.
Three?
Trójka?
Fight or flee?
Walczymy czy uciekamy?
You seem to be spoiling for a fight.
Nastawiałeś się na walkę.
If so, this is the ideal location for it.
To idealne miejsce.
Don't be ridiculous!
Nie żartuj!
I won't do this at the school!
Nie mogę walczyć w szkole.
Izumi-kun!
Izumi-kun!
It's okay. You'll be safe.
Będziesz bezpieczna.
It's okay!
Wszystko gra!
You'll be safe now.
Będziesz już bezpieczna.
Is he…
Czy on…?
Izumi-kun?
Izumi-kun?
Stop! I've lost them.
Stój! Zgubiłem ich.
They've put more than 300 meters between us.
Są ponad 300 metrów od nas.
It seems they are on foot.
Zdaje się, że są pieszo.
Three coming for us at once?
Trzech na raz?
In this scenario,
Powinniśmy spróbować pokonać ich pojedynczo.
One by one.
Po kolei.
Okay, let's give it a try.
Spróbujmy.
No, never mind.
Nie.
Forget that strategy.
Zapomnij.
Why?
Dlaczego?
I'm sleepy.
Jestem śpiący.
I'll be out for four hours.
Daj mi cztery godziny.
Why now?
Czemu teraz?
I can't help it.
Nic nie poradzę.
It's a physiological phenomenon.
Taki już jestem.
You should just stay on the move.
Lepiej się nie zatrzymuj.
In a straight line when possible.
Uciekaj jak najdalej.
That's our only option right now.
Teraz to nasza jedyna opcja.
I'm on my own for four hours?
Zostaję sam na cztery godziny?
I guess I can take a small breather.
Mogę chwilę odetchnąć.
Two more hours.
Zostały dwie godziny. Raczej mnie nie dogonią.
A taxi?
Taksówka?
No way!
Niemożliwe!
Oh, keep the change.
Reszta dla pana.
Just one?
Tylko jeden?
Can't be them, then.
Więc to nie oni.
Hello!
Cześć!
This place is nice.
Ładnie tu.
No one around and it's quiet.
Nikogo w pobliżu, cisza.
He's smiling.
Uśmiecha się.
He can't be a parasite, then.
To nie może być pasożyt.
But you really took off in a panic, huh?
Uciekłeś w panice.
And I'd heard that you're a tough one.
A podobno jesteś taki groźny.
What?
Co?
Hey, isn't your right hand's signal a bit weak?
Osłabł ci sygnał w prawej ręce.
Oh, hey!
Hej!
Wait!
Poczekaj!
It's the first time I've met a parasite who's so expressive!
Jeszcze nie widziałem tak ekspresywnego pasożyta!
He's slower than I'd expected.
Jest powolny.
I thought parasites were able to maximize the physical potential of their host.
A pasożyty potrafią w pełni wykorzystać potencjał swoich ciał.
But maybe the other two are close by!
Może pozostała dwójka jest w pobliżu.
I can't let my guard down!
Muszę być ostrożny.
Where are you heading to?
Dokąd zmierzasz?
Want a ride, sonny?
Podwieźć cię?
Oh, thank you.
Dziękuję.
Wait a minute.
Momencik.
This old man.
Ten facet…
Could the dog be a parasite, too?
Pies też może być pasożytem?
No, it's too small.
Nie, jest za mały.
You sure you want off here?
Na pewno chcesz tu wysiąść?
Yes, thank you.
Tak, dziękuję.
Thank God he wasn't a parasite.
Całe szczęście, to nie był pasożyt.
It's been almost four hours now.
Minęły niemal cztery godziny.
I guess they gave up.
Chyba się poddali.
Maybe I was wrong.
Może się myliłem.
Migi.
Migi.
Migi!
Migi!
Oh, Shinichi.
O, Shinichi.
I'm glad you're okay.
Dobrze, że nic ci nie jest.
-Three! -Yeah.
- Trójka! - Tak.
I still don't know where the other two are.
Wciąż nie wiem, gdzie jest pozostała dwójka.
That's not what I mean.
- Cała trójka jest w tym ciele. - Co?
So is it "Migi" because he's on your right hand?
Mówisz mu „Migi”, bo masz go w prawej dłoni?
That's so simplistic. You're just like me.
A to ciekawe.
Oh, I'm "Miki".
Bo ja jestem Miki.
This is a surprise.
A to niespodzianka.
We've won this fight.
Zwycięstwo jest nasze.
Next time, "Happy Family."
Następny odcinek: „Szczęśliwa rodzinka”